[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Management within your organization has defined a use case to support the confidentiality of data stored in a database. Which of the following solutions will BEST meet this need?",
    "options": [
      "Hashing",
      "Disk redundancies",
      "Encryption",
      "Patching"
    ],
    "correct": "Encryption",
    "explanation": "Encyption is the best choice to provide confidentiality for any type of data, including data stored in a database."
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Moe manages network devices in his store and maintains copies of the configuration files for all the managed routers and siwtches. On a weekly basis, he creates hashes for these files and compares them with hashes he created on the same files the previous week. Which of the following use cases is he MOST likely supporting?",
    "options": [
      "Supporting confidentiality",
      "Supporting integrity",
      "Supporting encryption",
      "Supporting availability"
    ],
    "correct": "Supporting integrity",
    "explanation": "He is most likely using a use case of supporting integrity. By verifying that the hashes of the configuration files have not changed, he can ensure that the files have not been altered or tampered with."
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following is a cryptographic algorithm that will create a fixed-length output from a data file but cannot be used to re-create the original data file?",
    "options": [
      "MD5",
      "AES",
      "IDS",
      "SIEM"
    ],
    "correct": "MD5",
    "explanation": "Message Digest 5 (MD5) is a hashing algorithm that creates a fixed-length IRREVERSIBLE output. Hashing algorithms cannot re-create the original data file from just the hash. AES you can re-create the original data file by decrypting it"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Your organization hosts an e-commerce web server selling digital products. The server randomly experiences a high volume of sales and usage, which causes spikes in resource usage. These spikes occasionally take the server down. Which of the following would be the BEST way to prevent these outages?",
    "options": [
      "Elasticity",
      "Scalability",
      "Normalization",
      "Stored procedures"
    ],
    "correct": "Elasticity",
    "explanation": "Elasticity is the best choice because it allows the server to dynamically scale as needed in response to changes in demand."
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "An administrator recently installed an IDS to help reduce the imapct of security incidents. Which of the following BEST identifies the control type of an IDS?",
    "options": [
      "Preventive",
      "Physical",
      "Deterrent",
      "Detective"
    ],
    "correct": "Detective",
    "explanation": "An intrusion detection system (IDS) is a detective control. It can detect malicious traffic after it enters a network but cannot prevent it from entering."
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Maggie works in the security section of the IT department. Her primary responsibilites are to monitor security logs, analyze trends reported by the SIEM, and validate alerts. Which of the following choices BEST identifies the primary security control she's implemnting?",
    "options": [
      "Compensating Control",
      "Preventive control",
      "Detective control",
      "Corrective control"
    ],
    "correct": "Detective control",
    "explanation": "Monitoring security logs, analyzing trend reports from a security information and event management (SIEM), and validating alerts from a SIEM are detective controls. Detective controls try to detect security incidents after they happened."
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "A server in your network's DMZ was recently attacked. The firewall logs show that the server was attacked from many different external IP addresses. It received an overwhelming number of requests from those addresses that caused the website hosted on the server to fail. What security goal was most directly affected by this attack?",
    "options": [
      "Integrity",
      "Non-repudiation",
      "Confidentiality",
      "Availability"
    ],
    "correct": "Availability",
    "explanation": "This attack disrupted the ability of legitimate users to access the website hosted on the server, which is an attack against the availability of that website."
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "You are in the process of logging into a service hosted by your organization. You entered your username and now you are being asked to complete a fingerprint scan. What element of access control is taking place when you scan your fingerprint?",
    "options": [
      "Authentication",
      "Authorization",
      "Availability",
      "Identification"
    ],
    "correct": "Authentication",
    "explanation": "The three streps of the access control process are identification, authentication, and authorization. You already completed the identification step by entering your username. The fingerprint scan is the authentication step, which verifies that you are who you say you are."
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Which one of the following technologies is generally NOT considered a fault tolerance or redundancy control?",
    "options": [
      "UPS",
      "SIEM",
      "RAID",
      "Identification"
    ],
    "correct": "SIEM",
    "explanation": "A security information and event mangement (SIEM) system is designed to improve the organization's ability to monitor and manage security issues. It does not generally provide redudancy or fault tolerance."
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Kate's manager asked her to organize a new process for conducting periodic vulnerability assessments of her organization's infrastructure. She is working to create a standard operating procedure for this scanning. What category BEST describes the control she is creating?",
    "options": [
      "Technical",
      "Detective",
      "Physical",
      "Managerial"
    ],
    "correct": "Managerial",
    "explanation": "The focus on policy and procedure and lack of mentioning technology causes the BEST possible solution to be Managerial."
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Lisa is logging into a system and, before typing her username and password, sees the message: This is a U.S. Government computer system, which may be accessed and used only for authorized Government business by authorized personnel. Unauthorized access or use of this computer system may subject violators to criminal, civil, and/or administrative action. What type of control is Lisa experncing?",
    "options": [
      "Detective",
      "Compensating",
      "Deterrent",
      "Corrective"
    ],
    "correct": "Deterrent",
    "explanation": "The purpose of a warning banner such as the one shown in this question is to make an intruder less likely to attempt an attack. That is the goal of a deterrent control."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "You are investigating an active security incident and you want to view the contents of network traffic that passed between two systems. What data source would BEST provide this information?",
    "options": [
      "Operating system log",
      "Application log",
      "Firewall log",
      "Packet capture"
    ],
    "correct": "Packet capture",
    "explanation": "Investigators looking into an active security incident may use a packet capture tool like Wireshark to capture network traffic related to the incident that they can later examine in careful detail to reconstruct what happened. Firewall logs may contain records of the systemss that communicated with each other, but they would not normally contain the content of that communication"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Moe is overwhelmed by the number of log records generated by the many different security systems in his organization and would like to use a technology that aggregates those records in a single location and correlates them. What technology would best meet his needs?",
    "options": [
      "Syslog",
      "SIEM",
      "IPS",
      "Firewall"
    ],
    "correct": "SIEM",
    "explanation": "A security information and event managment (SIEM) solution is designed to aggregate and correlate log entries."
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Maggie is reviewing log entries from many different systems and notices that the clocks on those systems are not synchronized, making it difficult to correlate the log entries. What protocol can she use to synchronize the system clocks?",
    "options": [
      "NTP",
      "FTP",
      "SFTP",
      "HTTPS"
    ],
    "correct": "NTP",
    "explanation": "The network time protocol (NTP) is used to synchronize system clocks with a centralized time source."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "domain": "1.0 - Mastering Security Basics",
    "question": "Which of the following describes the proper format of log entries for Linux systems?",
    "options": [
      "Event Viewer",
      "logger",
      "SIEM",
      "Syslog"
    ],
    "correct": "Syslog",
    "explanation": "The syslog protocol (defined in RFC 5424) identifies the format of Linux log entries and descirbes how to transpfor these log entries."
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Your organization wants to identify biometric methods used for identification. The requirements are... Collect the data passively, Bypass a formal enrollment process, and Avoid obvious methods and let the subject know data is being collected... Which of the following biometric methods BEST meet these requirements? (Select TWO).",
    "options": ["Fingerprint", "Retina", "Facial and Gait analysis", "Facial", "Palm Vein", "Gait analysis"],
    "correct": ["Facial and Gait analysis"],
    "explanation": "It's possible to collect facial scan data and perform gait analysis without an enrollment process. You would use cameras to observe subjects from a distance and collect the data passively."
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Your organization recently updated an online application employees use to log on when working from home. Employees enter their username and password into the application from their smartphone and the application logs their location using GPS. Which type of authentication is being used?",
    "options": [
      "One-factor",
      "Dual-factor",
      "something you are",
      "something you have"
    ],
    "correct": "One-factor",
    "explanation": "This is using one-factor authentication--something you know. The application uses the username for identification and the password for authentication. Note that even though the application logs the GPS location, it does not use that information for authentication."
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Mangement with your organization wants to add 2FA security for users working from home. Additionally, management wants to ensure that 2FA passwords expire after 30 seconds. Which of the following choices BEST meets this requirement?",
    "options": [
      "HOTP",
      "TOTP",
      "SMS",
      "Kerberos"
    ],
    "correct": "TOTP",
    "explanation": "A Time-based One-Time Password (TOTP) meets the requirements of two-factor authentication (2FA)."
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Management within your organization has decided to implement a biometric solution for authentication into the data center. They have stated that the biometric system needs to be highly accurate. Which of the following provides the BEST indication of accuracy with a biometric system?",
    "options": [
      "The lowest possible FRR",
      "The highest possible FAR",
      "The lowest possible CER",
      "The highest possible CER"
    ],
    "correct": "The lowest possible CER",
    "explanation": "A lower crossover error rate (CER) indicates a more accurate biometric system."
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "The Marvin Monroe Memorial Hostpital was recently sued after removing a kidney from the wrong patient. Hospital executives want to implement a method that will reduce medical errors related to misidentifying patients. They want to ensure medical personnel can identify a patient even if the patient is unconscious. Which of the following would be the BEST solution?",
    "options": [
      "Gait analysis",
      "Vein scans",
      "Retina scan",
      "voice recognition"
    ],
    "correct": "Vein scans",
    "explanation": "A vein scan implemented with a plam scanner would be the best solution of the available choices. The patient would place their palm on the scanner for biometric identification, or if the patient is unconscious, medical personnel can place the patient's palm on the scanner."
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Users regularly log on with a username and password. However, managment wants to add a second authentication factor for any users who launch the gcga application. The method needs to be user-friendly and non-disruptive. Which of the following will BEST meet these requirements?",
    "options": [
      "An authentication application",
      "TPM",
      "HSM",
      "Push notfications"
    ],
    "correct": "Push notfications",
    "explanation": "Push notifications are user-friendly and non-disruptive. Users receive a notification on a smartphone or tablet and can often acknowledge it by simply pressing a button."
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Your organization hires students during the summer for temporary help? They need access to network resources, but only during working hours. Managment has stressed that it is critically important to safegaurd trade secrets and other confidential information. Which of the following account managment concepts would be MOST important to meet these goals?",
    "options": [
      "Account expiration",
      "Account lockout",
      "Time-of-day restrictions",
      "Password recovery",
      "Password history"
    ],
    "correct": "Time-of-day restrictions",
    "explanation": "Time-of-day restrictions should be implemented to ensure that temporary workers can only access network resources during work hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "You need to provide a junior administrator with appropriate credentials to rebuild a domain controller after it suffers a catastrophic failure. Of the following choices, what type of account would BEST meet this need?",
    "options": [
      "User account",
      "Generic account",
      "Guest account",
      "Service account"
    ],
    "correct": "User account",
    "explanation": "A user account is the best choice of the available answers. More specifically, it would be a user account with administrative privileges (also known as a privileged account) so that the administrator can add the domain controller."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Lisa is reviewing an organization's account management process. She wants to ensure that security log entries accurately report the identity of personnel taking specific actions. Which of the following steps would BEST meet this requirement?",
    "options": [
      "Implementing generic accounts",
      "Implement role-based privileges",
      "Use an SSo solution",
      "Remove all shared accounts"
    ],
    "correct": "Remove all shared accounts",
    "explanation": "Removing all shared accounts is the best answer of the available choices. If two employees are using the same account, and one employee maliciously deletes data in a database, it would be impossible to determine which employee was responsible."
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "A recent security audit discovered several apparently dormant user accounts. Although users could log on to the accounts, no one had logged on to them for more than 60 days. You later discovered that these accounts are for contractors who work approximately one week every quarter. Which of the following is the BEST response to this situation?",
    "options": [
      "Remove the account expiration from the accounts",
      "Delete the accounts",
      "Reset the accounts",
      "Disable the accounts"
    ],
    "correct": "Disable the accounts",
    "explanation": "The best response is to disable the accounts and then enable them when needed by contractors."
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "A software developer is creating an application that must acces files stored in the user's Google Drive. What is the best way for the user to grant the application access to their Google account?",
    "options": [
      "OpenID Connect",
      "Provide their Google password each time they log into the application",
      "OAuth",
      "Store their Google password in the application"
    ],
    "correct": "OAuth",
    "explanation": "The OAuth authorization protocol is explicitly designed for this type of situation. Users of the application can grant the application limited access to resources in their Google account without disclosing their credentials."
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Web developers in your organization are creating a web application that will interact with other applications running on the internet. They want their application to receive user credentials from an app running on a trusted partner's web domain. Which of the following is the BEST choice to meet this need?",
    "options": [
      "SSO",
      "SAML",
      "Kerberos",
      "RADIUS"
    ],
    "correct": "SAML",
    "explanation": "Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) is a single sign-on (SSO) soultion used for web-based applications and would meet this requirement. All SSO solutions are not web-based, so SSO is not the best answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "Artie has been working at Ziffcorp as an accountant. However, after a disagreement with his boss, he decides to leave the company and gives a two-week notice. He has a user account allowing him to access network resources. Which of the following is the MOST appropriate step to take?",
    "options": [
      "Ensure his account is disabled when he announces that he is leaving the company",
      "immediately terminate his employment",
      "Force him to take a mandatory vacation",
      "Ensure his account is disabled during his exit interview"
    ],
    "correct": "Ensure his account is disabled during his exit interview",
    "explanation": "His account should be disabled during his exit interview."
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "You administer access control for users in your organization. Some departments have a high employee turnover, so you want to simplify account administration. Which of the following is the BEST choice?",
    "options": [
      "User-assigned privileges",
      "Group-based privileges",
      "Domain-assigned privileges",
      "Network-assigned privileges"
    ],
    "correct": "Group-based privileges",
    "explanation": "Group-based privileges are a form of role-based access control and they simplify administration."
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "domain": "2.0 - Understanding Identity and Access Managment",
    "question": "An administrator needs to grant users access to different shares on file servers based on their job functions. Which of the following access control schemes would BEST meet this need?",
    "options": [
      "Discrentionary access control",
      "Mandatory access control",
      "Role-based access control",
      "Rule-based access control"
    ],
    "correct": "Role-based access control",
    "explanation": "The role-based access control (role-BAC) scheme is the best choice for assigning access based on job functions."
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "An outside consultant performed an audit on the Municipal House of Pancakes network. She identified a legacy protocol being used to access browser-based interfaces on switches and routers with the network. She recommended replacing the legacy protocol with a secure protocol to access these network devices using the same interface. Which of the following protocoles should be implemented?",
    "options": ["The newest fully supported version of SSL", "The newest fully supported version of TLS", "The newest fully supported version of LDAPS", "The newest fully supported version of SNMP"],
    "correct": "The newest fully supported version of TLS",
    "explanation": "The newest version of Transport Layer Security (TLS) should be implemented to access the network devices."
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Your organization's security policy requires that confidential data transferred over the internal network must be encrypted. Which of the following protocols would BEST meet this requirement?",
    "options": [
      "FTP",
      "SSH", 
      "SNMPV3", 
      "SRTP"],
    "correct": "SSH",
    "explanation": "You can use Secure Shell (SSH) to encrypt confidential data when transmitting it over the network."
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Maggie needs to collect network device configuration information and network statistics from devices on the network. She wants to protect the confidentiality of credentials used to connect to these devices. Which of the follow protocols would BEST meet this need?",
    "options": [
      "SSH",
      "FTP", 
      "SNMPV3", 
      "TLS"],
    "correct": "SNMPV3",
    "explanation": "Simple Network Management Protocol version 3 (SNMPv3) is a secure protocol that can monitor and collect information from network devices. It includes strong authentication mechanisms to protect the confidentiality of credentials."
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Which one of the following components would not be able to communicate on the data plane of a zero trust network?",
    "options": [
      "subject",
      "Enterprise resource", 
      "Policy enforcement point", 
      "Policy administrator"],
    "correct": "Policy administrator",
    "explanation": "The Policy Adminstrator (PA) exists entirely on the control plane. It sends decisions to the Policy Enforcement Point (PEP), wich is able to communicate on both the control plane and the data plane."
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "You are configuring a web server that will contain information about your organization and receive orders from your customers. which one of the following network locations is the best placement for this server?",
    "options": [
      "Screen subnet",
      "Intranet", 
      "Extranet", 
      "Internet"],
    "correct": "Screen subnet",
    "explanation": "Systems that must be accessed by the general public should always be placed on the screen subnet. This network is designed to house systems that require public access but still must be secured."
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Maggie is examining traffic on a network searching for signs of insecure protocol use. She sees communications taking place on several different network ports. Which one of these ports most likely contains insecure traffic?",
    "options": [
      "22",
      "80", 
      "443", 
      "587"],
    "correct": "80",
    "explanation": "Port 80 is used by the unecrypted Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)."
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "You are tasked with enabling NTP on some servers within your organization's screened subnet. Which of the following use cases are you MOST likely supporting with this action?",
    "options": [
      "Encryping voice and video transmissions",
      "Providing time synchronization", 
      "Enabling email usage", 
      "Encrypting data in transit"],
    "correct": "Providing time synchronization",
    "explanation": "The Network Time Protocol (NTP) provides time synchronization services, so enabling NTP on servers in the screen sunet would meet this use case."
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Your organization has several switches in use throughout the internal network. Management wants to implement a security control to prevent unatuhorized access to these switches within the network. Which of the following choices would BEST meet this need?",
    "options": [
      "Disable unused ports",
      "Disable STP", 
      "Enable SSH", 
      "Enable DHCP"],
    "correct": "Disable unused ports",
    "explanation": "You can prevent unathorized access by disabling unused physical ports on the switches as an overall port security practice. This prevents the connection if someone plugs their computer into an unused disabled port."
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Network administrators manage network devices remotely. However, a recent security audit discovered they are using a protocol that allows them to send credentials over the network in cleartext. Which of the following is the best method to be adopted to eliminate this vulnerability?",
    "options": [
      "Use SNMPv2c",
      "Use SSH", 
      "Use SSL", 
      "Use SFTP"],
    "correct": "Use SSH",
    "explanation": "Secure Shell (SSH) can be used to connect to many network devices and is the best answer for the given choices."
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Which of the following devices would MOST likely have the following entries used to define its operation? 1. Permit IP any any eq 80 2. Permit IP any any eq 443 3. Deny IP any any",
    "options": [
      "Firewall",
      "Proxy server", 
      "Web server", 
      "Jump server"],
    "correct": "Firewall",
    "explanation": "These are rules in an access control list (ACL) with a firewall."
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Firewall rule question?",
    "options": [
      "HTTPS Outbound",
      "HTTP Outbound", 
      "DNS", 
      "Telnet"],
    "correct": "HTTP Outbound",
    "explanation": "The Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) rule should be changed from Allow to Block to block cleartext web traffic."
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "The Springfield Nuclear Power Plant has several stand-alone computers used for monitoring. Employees log on to these computers using a local account to verify proper operation of various processes. The CIO of the organization has mandated that these computers cannot be connected to the organization's network or have access to the internet. Which of the following would BEST meet this requirement?",
    "options": [
      "Air gap the computers",
      "Place the computers in a screened subnet", 
      "Create a separate isolated network for these comptuers", 
      "Place the computers within a VLAN"],
    "correct": "Air gap the computers",
    "explanation": "An air gap provides physical isolation, indicating that there is a gap of air between an isolated system and other systems."
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "You have added another router in your network. This router provides a path to a limited access network that isn't advertised. However, a network administrator needs to access this network regularly. Which of the following could he do to configure his computer to access this limited network?",
    "options": [
      "Implement QoS technolgies",
      "Add a VLAN", 
      "Use the route command", 
      "Open additional ports on the router"],
    "correct": "Use the route command",
    "explanation": "The route command can be used to display and manipulate the routing table on a Linux computer. Using this, you can provide another gateway path through this router to the limited access network."
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Several severs in your organization's screened subnet were recently attacked. After analyzing the logs, you discover that many of these attacks used TCP, but the packets were not part of an established TCP session. Which of the following devices would provide the BEST solution to prevent these attacks in the future?",
    "options": [
      "Stateless firewall",
      "Stateful firewall", 
      "Network firewall", 
      "Web application firewall"],
    "correct": "Stateful firewall",
    "explanation": "A stateful firewall filters traffic based on the state of the packet within a session. It would filter a packet that isn't part of an established Tansmission Control Protocol (TCP) session, which starts with a TCP three-way hand shake."
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "domain": "3.0 - Exploring Network Tecchnologies and Tools",
    "question": "Your network currently has a dedicated firewall protecting access to a web server. It is currently configured with only the following two rules in the ACL: PERMIT TCP ANY ANY 443 and PERMIT TCP ANY ANY 80. You have detected DNS requests and DNS zone transfer requests coming through the fire-wall and you need to block them. Which of the following would meet this goal?",
    "options": [
      "Add the following rule to the firewall: DENY UDP ALL ALL 53",
      "Add the following rule to the firewall: DENY TCP ALL ALL 53", 
      "Add the following rule to the firewall: DENY IP ALL ALL 53", 
      "Add an implicit deny rule at the end of the ACL",
      "Both DENY UDP ALL ALL 53 and implicit deny rule at the end of the ACL"],
    "correct": "Both DENY UDP ALL ALL 53 and implicit deny rule at the end of the ACL",
    "explanation": "The easiest way is to add an implicit deny rule at the end of the access control list (ACL) and all firewalls should have this to black all unwanted traffic. You can also deny all IP traffic using port 53 with DENY IP ALL ALL 53."
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "domain": "4.0 - Securing Your Network",
    "question": "A HIDS reported a vulnerability on a system based on a known attack. After researching the alert from the HIDS, you identify the recommended soltuon and begin applying it. What type of HIDS is in use?",
    "options": [
      "Network-based",
      "Signature-based", 
      "Heuristic-based", 
      "Anomaly-based"],
    "correct": "Signature-based",
    "explanation": "If the host-based intrustion detection system (HIDS) identified a known issue, it is using signature-based detection (sometimes called definition-based detection)."
  }
]
